hornady.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy - Hornady Manufacturing, Inc

This Privacy Policy covers the website www.hornady.com (the "Site"), which is owned and operated by Hornady Manufacturing Company, a Nebraska corporation (the "Company"). The Company is committed to protecting the privacy of all users of this Site. Your data will be maintained by the Company in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is an integral part of the Site. The privacy practices set forth herein have been established to provide the best services to you and to keep all your personally identifiable information private. Personal information includes, but is not limited to, name, address, phone number, racial data, political affiliation, or sexual orientation. Personal information does not include information that is encoded or anonymized, or publicly available information that has not been combined with non-public personal information. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy in whole, you must not use the Site.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please [contact us](https://www.hornady.com/contact/) or call us at (308) 382-1390.

### 1\. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY THE SITE.

In general, the Site will not collect any personally identifiable information that is not voluntarily supplied by the user. While the site may collect behavior and vicinities of people who visit, the Site will not collect any personally identifiable information when you are browsing the Site. This information is aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the Site, pages viewed, etc., to measure the use of our Site and improve its performance and content.

Certain actions on the Site require you to provide personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card number, and any other information that is necessary to complete that action, but no personally identifiable information will be obtained other than the information you enter. The actions that require your personal information include, but are not limited to, online purchases, requests for catalogs or application for membership to Hornady clubs. The Site reserves the right to store your name and contact information in a database solely for the reasons set forth below indefinitely, or until you request its removal.

### 2\. USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION.

#### A. ONLINE PURCHASES.

The personally identifiable information that you voluntarily provide when you make an online purchase is necessary and will be used to complete the transaction through the Site and to ship the product to you. For your additional safety, the Site will not store your credit card number submitted for a transaction after the transaction is complete. You will be required to re-enter your credit card number for each transaction that requires a credit card.

#### B. PROVIDING REQUESTED SERVICES.

The Site will use personal information to provide the services requested by you. For example, if you request a catalog, the Site will use your address to mail you a catalog.

#### C. AGGREGATE INFORMATION.

The Site may use your name and contact information to compile aggregated demographic information for market studies, data trending, or similar uses that will make the services offered by the Site more effective and useful. Any aggregated information will be used solely by the Company, and stored indefinitely, or until you request its removal. The aggregated information and studies will not be linked to any personally identifiable information, and the Site will not sell or release any personally identifiable information to any third party.

#### D. VERIFICATION/OFFERS.

The Company may contact you via the email address or telephone number you entered on the Site to verify your purchases, as the Company deems to be in your best interest. If you have opted-in to receive marketing materials, the Company will store your information indefinitely, and may also use your email address to send you special offers and/or updates solely relating to the Site. The Company will not use your telephone number or email address for any third party advertisements or notices. If the Company decides to provide email offers, you will have the opportunity to opt out of any emails by selecting the "unsubscribe" link embedded in the email message, or by notifying the Company via email at [webmaster@hornady.com](mailto:webmaster@hornady.com) or via telephone at (308) 382-1390.

#### E. THIRD PARTIES

Some functions of the Site require that third parties receive data from forms completed by users of the Site. These third parties each maintain their own terms of use and privacy policies, which can be viewed by clicking the links below.

  * Email Marketing Service: [Privacy Policy](https://myemma.com/legal/privacy-statement) | [Terms of Use](https://myemma.com/legal/terms-of-use)
  * Mailing House: [Privacy Policy](http://www.datapeak.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Datapeak-Inc.-GDPR-Privacy-Policy-May-17-2018.docx)
  * Hosting Company: [Privacy Policy](https://totalchoicehosting.com/privacy-policy.html) | [Acceptable Use Policy](https://totalchoicehosting.com/web-hosting-aup.html)

#### F. EMAIL

We collect email addresses in multiple points on the site. For transactions and support, by providing us your email, we will send you messages in response to inquiries or transactions. To help us track your response or potential bounces (or lack there of), we may receive notification if you have received, opened, or clicked any links in an email from us. For historical reference for any future customer support measures, we may store this information indefinitely, or until you request its removal.

For marketing purposes, including but not limited to signing up for Team Hornady, promotion entries, or dealer listing sign-ups, the option to subscribe to future marketing messages is provided. Should you opt in, you are consenting to receive messages to the information you provided. To help us track email performance and interest, we will receive information regarding bounces, opens, or links which have been clicked. Hornady uses MyEmma to store personal information and distribute marketing email messages. Their privacy policy can be reviewed on [myemma.com](https://myemma.com/legal/privacy-notice). Information will be stored indefinitely, or until you request its removal.

You can opt out of any emails by selecting the "unsubscribe" link embedded in the email message, or by notifying the Company via email at [webmaster@hornady.com](mailto:webmaster@hornady.com) or via telephone at (308) 382-1390. Otherwise, your information will be stored indefinitely or until you request its removal.

#### G. WARRANTIES

All qualified products may be registered online to be covered by a warranty. Personal information gathered is stored in an online database to assist with future customer service requests and claims. Information is stored indefinitely, or until you request its removal.

#### H. ORDER STATUS

A user can enter their information to check the real-time status of their order. Tracking status information is stored in the website for up to one month after the delivery date, so users can monitor their purchase and when they will receive it. Information can be removed from this tool by contacting the Company via email at [webmaster@hornady.com](mailto:webmaster@hornady.com) or via telephone at (308) 382-1390.

#### I. ORDER DETAILS

A user can access their past transaction history affiliated with their email address by creating a profile. Order history is stored in the website indefinitely, so users can monitor their purchase status, and access past information in case of customer service support, reordering products, or any other need. Information can be removed from this tool by contacting the Company via email at [webmaster@hornady.com](mailto:webmaster@hornady.com) or via telephone at (308) 382-1390.

### 3\. USER UPLOADED CONTENT.

Certain features of this Site allow users to upload or submit photos, stories, testimonials, or materials to the Site for others to view or access ("User Content"). If you upload or submit User Content of any kind, you warrant and represent: (i) that you own or otherwise control all of the rights to the User Content that you post; (ii) that the User Content is accurate; (iii) that use of the User Content you supply does not violate this policy and/or the terms of use of this Site; and (iv) that you will indemnify the Company for all claims resulting from User Content you supply. Additionally, you grant the Company a nonexclusive, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, and fully sublicensable right to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, translate, create derivative works from, distribute, and display such User Content in all countries and in any media and/or form. You grant the Company and sublicensees the right to use the name that you submit in connection with such User Content, if they choose.

### 4\. COOKIES.

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer. Cookies are necessary for the Site's functionality. Cookies allow the Site to take data you enter on one page of the Site (e.g., the desired order information) and return results of your request on a new page. Cookies also tell us information when you return to the Site to make your visit to the Site more enjoyable.

You can disable cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent to your computer. However, this may affect your ability to shop or perform certain actions on this Site and elsewhere online.

Other partners, affiliates, and advertisers may include, but are not limited to, the list below. You can opt of out their cookies by visiting their links.

#### Essential

  * Google Tag Manager ([Opt-Out](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/)): Tracks and actions taken on website, and pushes metrics to linked websites for optimization
  * Google Analytics ([Opt-Out](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/)): Tracks and measures analytics, performance optimization
  * HotJar ([Opt-Out](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/)): Tracks and measures analytics, performance optimization

#### Marketing

  * Google Display Network ([Opt-Out](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en)): Serves digital ads and reports performance
  * Google AdWords ([Opt-Out](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en)): Serves digital ads and reports performance
  * DoubleClick ([Opt-Out](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en)): Serves digital ads and reports performance
  * Facebook Connect ([Opt-Out](http://www.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)): Serves digital ads and reports performance
  * LinkedIn ([Opt-Out](http://www.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)): Serves digital ads and reports performance
  * YouTube ([Opt-Out](http://www.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)): Serves digital ads and reports performance
  * Bing ([Opt-Out](https://account.microsoft.com/privacy/ad-settings/signedout)): Serves digital ads and reports performance

### 5\. SECURITY.

The importance of security for all of your personally identifiable information is of utmost concern to the Company. The Site exercises great care in providing secure transmission of your personal information. Secure socket layer (SSL) encryption is used for all credit card transactions. In addition, firewalls and other security enhancements are utilized by the Site to help protect your personal information.

Should you request the removal of your personal information from our systems, we will remove all available instances from marketing systems and online sources to the best of our ability. Personal information such as transaction history may be stored in an offline, secure server for business record keeping.

### 6\. LEGAL DISCLAIMER.

Notwithstanding the Company's policy against sharing any information you have provided, the Company will release any personal information when it believes disclosure is required by law and when it believes that the disclosure of your personal information is necessary to protect the Company's rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on the Company or the Site.

### 7\. LINKS/AFFILIATED WEBSITES.

This Site may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by the Company, including, but not limited to, the Company's partners, affiliates, and advertisers. This Privacy Policy applies only to the Site. The Company is not responsible for the privacy practices of any website that you may link to from the Site or from which you link to this Site. The Company encourages you to review the privacy policy of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

### 8\. MODIFICATION OF PRIVACY POLICY.

The Company reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Any modifications made will be posted on the Site. Please review the Privacy Policy frequently.

The effective date of this Privacy Policy is: May 24, 2018.

###### Past versions:
